<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!--
  Copyright (C) 2021 - 2022 FHNW (University of Applied Sciences and Arts Northwestern Switzerland)

  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at

       http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
  -->
<questionnaire xmlns="https://smesec.eu" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
               xsi:schemaLocation="https://smesec.eu https://smesec.eu/questionnaire.xsd"
               id="msesec-data-protection-and-security" readableName="Data Protection and Security (MSE)"
               version="1" order="0" language="en">
    <description>
        This coach focuses on Data Protection and Security for micro and small enterprises.
    </description>

    <attachments>
        <attachment id="icon">
            <content filename="assets/coach-icon.png"/>
        </attachment>
    </attachments>

    <questions>
        <question id="q2200" type="info" hidden="false">
            <introduction>Data Protection and Security</introduction>
            <text>Intro</text>
            <infotext>
                As a micro or small enterprise, you are also concerned with data protection and security matters varying from financial information
                details to personal information of your staff, clients or suppliers. Indeed, this topic is not only a legal necessity, but
                is also essential for protecting and preserving the continuity of your business.
            </infotext>
        </question>
        <!-- Priority 2 -->
        <question id="q2210" type="A" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-12">
            <introduction>
                Company's mobile devices have the potential to store large volumes of sensitive data whether that is about your
                business in general (call records, contacts, images, etc.), employees, clients or suppliers; therefore, if that data is
                compromised it could result in irreversible harm for your business.
            </introduction>
            <text>Is data on your company's mobile devices encrypted?</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2210o1">
                    <text>Yes, data is encrypted on all mobile devices.</text>
                </option>
                <option id="q2210o2">
                    <text>Generally yes, but there are exceptions.</text>
                    <comment>
                        Consider encrypting all your mobile devices. Indeed, nowadays almost all modern devices have a built-in setting for this.
                    </comment>
                </option>
                <option id="q2210o3">
                    <text>No, we don't encrypt data on mobile devices.</text>
                    <comment>
                        Encryption protects your data and is a necessary part of safeguarding your business. Start encrypting all mobile
                        devices of your company.
                    </comment>
                </option>
            </options>
            <metadata key="_cysec.logic">
                <mvalue key="default">
                    <stringValue>
                        TRUE : default : {
                        addScore("strengthMax", 2);
                        addScore("knowhowMax", 1);
                        addScore("uuMax", 2);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2210o1") : scoring : {
                        addScore("strength", 2);
                        addScore("knowhow", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 2);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2210o2") : scoring : {
                        addScore("strength", 1);
                        addScore("knowhow", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 1);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2210o3") : recEncryptMobileDevices : {
                        addRecommendation("recEncryptMobileDevices", 200, "", "", tn("recEncryptMobileDevices-title"),
                        tn("recEncryptMobileDevices-text"),
                        "", "app/coach.jsp?fqcn=msesec-data-protection-and-security.default&amp;question=q2210");
                        };
                        TRUE : recEncryptMobileDevices : {
                        revokeRecommendation("recEncryptMobileDevices");
                        };
                    </stringValue>
                </mvalue>
            </metadata>
            <instruction>
                <text>
                    &lt;p&gt;Nowadays, companies and in particular micro and small business rely on mobile devices (e.g. tablets or phones) for
                    day-to-day business. Some use them for taking customer's orders, make presentations, accept payments, get customer
                    signatures or even track and manage their expenses via applications. Therefore, it is critical that these devices are
                    properly configured as they contain valuable information/data about your business.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Most modern devices have some sort of feature to use
                    &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://csrc.nist.gov/glossary/term/encrypt"&gt;encryption&lt;/a&gt;.
                    If you have not activated encryption on your mobile devices yet, it is time to take action.&lt;/p&gt;
                </text>
            </instruction>
        </question>
        <question id="q2202" type="A" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-1">
            <introduction>
                Most companies keep sensitive information in different places. This data, for example, contains information where
                customers, employees or suppliers can be identified.
            </introduction>
            <text>Do you maintain an inventory of all sensitive information stored or processed by your organisation?</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2202o1">
                    <text>Yes</text>
                </option>
                <option id="q2202o2">
                    <text>No</text>
                    <comment>
                        The first step in keeping sensitive information safe is to know where such data is stored. Therefore, you should
                        create an inventory that shows where this information is stored or processed inside your organisation.
                    </comment>
                </option>
            </options>
            <metadata key="_cysec.logic">
                <mvalue key="default">
                    <stringValue>
                        TRUE : default : {
                        addScore("strengthMax", 1);
                        addScore("knowhowMax", 1);
                        addScore("uuMax", 1);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2202o1") : scoring : {
                        addScore("strength", 1);
                        addScore("knowhow", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 1);
                        };
                    </stringValue>
                </mvalue>
            </metadata>
            <instruction>
                <text>
                    &lt;p&gt;Sensitive data can take different forms. For example, according to the European Union
                    (&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://ec.europa.eu/justice/smedataprotect/index_en.htm"&gt;EU, 2022&lt;/a&gt;), the following
                    are considered as sensitive information which are subject to specific processing conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Personal data, this includes racial or ethnic origin, political opinion, religious beliefs.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Genetic and biometric data.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Health related data.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Address and localisation&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Income&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Online identifier&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;In addition, these may also be trade secrets, financial information or intellectual property rights.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;It is your company's task to check which of your services or products collect and process personal
                    data. For more information consult the European Union
                    &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://ec.europa.eu/justice/smedataprotect/index_en.htm"&gt;guideline for small businesses&lt;/a&gt;.
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                </text>
            </instruction>
        </question>
        <question id="q2225" type="A" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-5">
            <introduction>
                In order to avoid high fines and/or damage to your company's reputation. It is in your company's best interest to be aware
                and keep yourself informed about the regulations that apply or may impact your business.
            </introduction>
            <text>Are you aware the applicable provisions, laws and requirements of processing personal data in your region and/or the region of your customers?</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2225o1">
                    <text>Yes</text>
                    <comment>
                        This is very good. Keep in mind that new regulations may materialize in other countries. Therefore, revise new
                        applicable provisions that may apply to your business from time to time.
                    </comment>
                </option>
                <option id="q2225o2">
                    <text>No</text>
                    <comment>Please inform yourself about the applicable law/regulations/requirements that may apply to your business.</comment>
                </option>
                <option id="q2225o3">
                    <text>Partially</text>
                    <comment>Please inform yourself about all the applicable law/regulations/requirements that may apply to your business.</comment>
                </option>
            </options>
            <metadata key="_cysec.logic">
                <mvalue key="default">
                    <stringValue>
                        TRUE : default : {
                        addScore("strengthMax", 1);
                        addScore("knowhowMax", 1);
                        addScore("uuMax", 1);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2225o1") : scoring : {
                        addScore("strength", 1);
                        addScore("knowhow", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 1);
                        };
                        or( isSelected("q2225o2"), isSelected("q2225o3") ): recApplicableProvisions : {
                        addRecommendation("recApplicableProvisions", 200, "", "", tn("recApplicableProvisions-title"),
                        tn("recApplicableProvisions-text"),
                        "", "app/coach.jsp?fqcn=msesec-data-protection-and-security.default&amp;question=q2225");
                        };
                        TRUE : recApplicableProvisions : {
                        revokeRecommendation("recApplicableProvisions");
                        };
                    </stringValue>
                </mvalue>
            </metadata>
            <instruction>
                <text>
                    &lt;p&gt;For more information about the different jurisdictions and their corresponding laws in regard to personal
                    data, it is suggested that you consult the encompassing documentation provided by
                    &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.dataguidance.com/laws"&gt;Data Guidance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;It is also highly recommended that you have recourse to an attorney or an expert in global privacy laws who
                    you can provide guidance on how to apply these to your specific needs and circumstances if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
                </text>
            </instruction>
        </question>
        <question id="q2215" type="A" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-3">
            <introduction>
                If you are in contact with personal data, you are very likely processing it for some purpose, such as a storage, sharing,
                deleting or collecting.
            </introduction>
            <text>Do you PROCESS personal data securely?</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2215o1">
                    <text>Yes, we process data securely.</text>
                </option>
                <option id="q2215o2">
                    <text>No, we do not process data in a secure manner.</text>
                    <comment>
                        Not processing the data securely increases your exposure which could have very bad consequences. Review which
                        data regulations apply to your business and implement the right process procedures as soon as possible.
                    </comment>
                </option>
                <option id="q2215o3">
                    <text>We don't know.</text>
                    <comment>
                        Not processing the data securely only increases your exposure which could have very bad consequences. Review which
                        data regulations apply to your business and implement the right process procedures as soon as possible.
                    </comment>
                </option>
                <option id="q2215o4">
                    <text>We use a third party that process our data.</text>
                    <comment>
                        It is your duty to make sure that the third party processor provides the sufficient guarantees that they process
                        the data in a secure manner. Do not forget to verify this.
                    </comment>
                </option>
            </options>
            <metadata key="_cysec.logic">
                <mvalue key="default">
                    <stringValue>
                        not(isSelected("q2215o4")) : default : {
                        addScore("strengthMax", 1);
                        addScore("uuMax", 1);
                        };
                        or(isSelected("q2215o1")) : scoring : {
                        addScore("strength", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 1);
                        };
                        or( isSelected("q2215o2"), isSelected("q2215o3") ): recProcessDataSecurely : {
                        addRecommendation("recProcessDataSecurely", 200, "", "", tn("recProcessDataSecurely-title"),
                        tn("recProcessDataSecurely-text"),
                        "", "app/coach.jsp?fqcn=msesec-data-protection-and-security.default&amp;question=q2215");
                        };
                        TRUE : recProcessDataSecurely : {
                        revokeRecommendation("recProcessDataSecurely");
                        };
                    </stringValue>
                </mvalue>
            </metadata>
            <instruction>
                <text>
                    &lt;p&gt;Processing concerns "any action performed on data whether automated or manual"
                    (&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://gdpr.eu/what-is-gdpr/"&gt;GDPR EU, 2022&lt;/a&gt;). For example, if your business stores or
                    processes personal information from EU citizens within EU states, you are concerned with the General Data Protection
                    Regulation (GDPR).&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;In order to process data securely, it is highly recommended that your company:&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Ensure that your company has the legal basis for processing of personal data.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Only collect necessary data, i.e. do not process data that is not vital. This is also known as data minimisation.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Establish appropriate technical and organizational measures’ to securely handle the data. This can be done for
                    example by implementing end-to-end encryption.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Training your staff about how to securely handle the data. This also means limiting the access only to those
                    employees that really need to process and/or handle this information.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                </text>
            </instruction>
        </question>
        <question id="q2217" type="A" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-3">
            <introduction>
                Handling and storing data go hand in hand. As a micro or small business you are also concerned with this. As it is the case
                for nearly all companies, it is very likely your company holds sensitive data that needs to be kept safe from attacks,
                theft or unwarranted access. Thus, it is important to store this information securely.
            </introduction>
            <text>Do you STORE personal data securely?</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2217o1">
                    <text>Yes</text>
                </option>
                <option id="q2217o2">
                    <text>No</text>
                    <comment>
                        It is critical that you amend this and start to implement security practices and procedures to store sensitive
                        data securely from external or internal threats.
                    </comment>
                </option>
                <option id="q2217o3">
                    <text>We don't know</text>
                    <comment>
                        It is critical that you amend this and start to implement security practices and procedures to store sensitive
                        data securely from external or internal threats.
                    </comment>
                </option>
            </options>
            <metadata key="_cysec.logic">
                <mvalue key="default">
                    <stringValue>
                        TRUE : default : {
                        addScore("strengthMax", 1);
                        addScore("knowhowMax", 1);
                        addScore("uuMax", 1);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2217o1") : scoring : {
                        addScore("strength", 1);
                        addScore("knowhow", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 1);
                        };
                        or( isSelected("q2217o2"), isSelected("q2217o3") ): recSaveDataSecurely : {
                        addRecommendation("recSaveDataSecurely", 200, "", "", tn("recSaveDataSecurely-title"),
                        tn("recSaveDataSecurely-text"),
                        "", "app/coach.jsp?fqcn=msesec-data-protection-and-security.default&amp;question=q2217");
                        };
                        TRUE : recSaveDataSecurely : {
                        revokeRecommendation("recSaveDataSecurely");
                        };
                    </stringValue>
                </mvalue>
            </metadata>
            <instruction>
                <text>
                    &lt;p&gt;If your company stores sensitive data, you need to make sure that this data is stored securely. It is critical
                    that you check the legal requirements that concern your company. Keep in mind that nowadays governments outside Europe
                    have also started to enact data-privacy regulations that may apply to you.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, make sure to you ask yourself whether there are laws that require your company to keep sensitive
                    data secure? Consider the following aspects for storing data securely.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Restrict confidential data to the office.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Don't transfer unencrypted data over the internet.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Delete sensitive data that is no longer needed.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Encrypt backups.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;For more information please consult the proposed resources below:&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://gdpr.eu/article-32-security-of-processing/"&gt;Article 32 of the EU General Data Protection Regulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/collection/protecting-bulk-personal-data"&gt;Protecting bulk personal data by the UK National cyber security centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                </text>
            </instruction>
        </question>
        <question id="q2220" type="A" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-6">
            <introduction>
                Compliance and implementation of the data protection regulations is key to the continuity of your business.
            </introduction>
            <text>Do you implement the current data protection regulations consistently and correctly?</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2220o1">
                    <text>Yes</text>
                    <comment>That is great. Make sure to review the different requirements at least once per year.</comment>
                </option>
                <option id="q2220o2">
                    <text>No or we don't know</text>
                    <comment>
                        It is critical that you comply with data regulations that may concern you. The cost of failing to comply with the
                        rules can be high (varying from warnings to expensive fines) and burdensome. Get informed about these regulations
                        and start implementing them.
                    </comment>
                </option>
                <option id="q2220o3">
                    <text>Partially</text>
                    <comment>
                        It is critical that you fully comply with data regulations that may concern you. The cost of failing to comply
                        with the rules can be high (varying from warnings to expensive fines) and burdensome.
                    </comment>
                </option>
            </options>
            <metadata key="_cysec.logic">
                <mvalue key="default">
                    <stringValue>
                        TRUE : default : {
                        addScore("strengthMax", 1);
                        addScore("knowhowMax", 1);
                        addScore("uuMax", 1);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2220o1") : scoring : {
                        addScore("strength", 1);
                        addScore("knowhow", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 1);
                        };
                        or( isSelected("q2220o2"), isSelected("q2220o3") ): recRegulationsComplianceImplementation : {
                        addRecommendation("recRegulationsComplianceImplementation", 200, "", "", tn("recRegulationsComplianceImplementation-title"),
                        tn("recRegulationsComplianceImplementation-text"),
                        "", "app/coach.jsp?fqcn=msesec-data-protection-and-security.default&amp;question=q2220");
                        };
                        TRUE : recRegulationsComplianceImplementation : {
                        revokeRecommendation("recRegulationsComplianceImplementation");
                        };
                    </stringValue>
                </mvalue>
            </metadata>
            <instruction>
                <text>
                    &lt;p&gt;Compliance and implementation of the data protection regulations is key to the continuity of your business.
                    It will enable your company to maintain their reputation and increase internal as well as external confidence.
                    Moreover, by complying with the regulations it ensures that the data is safe from harm that otherwise could result
                    in a very costly and time-consuming undertaking.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Failing to implement the regulations consistently and correctly results in a failure of law compliance. Hence,
                    it is critical that your company's enacts guidelines and employs technology that will and can align with the different
                    regulations that may concern your business.&lt;/p&gt;
                </text>
            </instruction>
        </question>
        <!-- Priority 3 -->
        <question id="q2230" type="A" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-10">
            <introduction>
                Data breaches are undesirable and need to be avoided at all costs. Indeed, micro and small business are also targets of
                malicious actors, and thus need to be prepared and invest time and resources to prevent these type of incidents.
            </introduction>
            <text>Do you take appropriate measures against data breach?</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2230o1">
                    <text>Yes</text>
                </option>
                <option id="q2230o2">
                    <text>No</text>
                    <comment>
                        Data breaches can have serious consequences. Consider putting into place the right measures as proposed in the
                        instruction text.
                    </comment>
                </option>
            </options>
            <metadata key="_cysec.logic">
                <mvalue key="default">
                    <stringValue>
                        TRUE : default : {
                        addScore("strengthMax", 1);
                        addScore("knowhowMax", 1);
                        addScore("uuMax", 1);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2230o1") : scoring : {
                        addScore("strength", 1);
                        addScore("knowhow", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 1);
                        };
                    </stringValue>
                </mvalue>
            </metadata>
            <instruction>
                <text>
                    &lt;p&gt;A data breach "occurs when information held by an organisation is stolen or accessed without authorisation"
                    (&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/guidance/data-breaches#section_1"&gt;NCSC, 2022&lt;/a&gt;) resulting a
                    breach of confidentiality, availability or integrity. Thus, it is in your company's best interest to prevent and also
                    be prepared in case such a scenario would happen. Keep in mind the following aspects:&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Train your staff regularly in cybersecurity topics. Indeed, a lot of data breaches happen by
                    tricking employees into revealing their company's credentials (whether they are aware or unaware of it).&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Follow cybersecurity guidelines that tackle the processing, handling and storing of personal data.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Enable antivirus protections to help guard against malware that could steal or damage credentials.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;If a data breach happens, notify the affected parties whether it is your customers, employers, suppliers or
                    other data.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;For more information consult
                    &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.oaic.gov.au/privacy/notifiable-data-breaches/preventing-data-breaches-advice-from-the-australian-cyber-security-centre"&gt;this advice&lt;/a&gt;
                    from the Australian Cyber Security Centre.&lt;/p&gt;
                </text><!--- Source: https://www.fcc.gov/general/cybersecurity-small-business -->
            </instruction>
        </question>
        <question id="q2235" type="Astar" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-2">
            <introduction>
                The CIA triad (confidentiality, integrity and availability) is a security concept that all enterprises regardless of their
                size need to be familiar with as it highlights the three key elements of information security. These will be helpful to
                ensure that your company's data and/or the data that is processed can be protected.
            </introduction>
            <text>The data stored in your company's systems is protected against violations of ...</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2235o1">
                    <text>confidentiality</text>
                </option>
                <option id="q2235o2">
                    <text>integrity</text>
                </option>
                <option id="q2235o3">
                    <text>availability</text>
                </option>
            </options>
            <metadata key="_cysec.logic">
                <mvalue key="default">
                    <stringValue>
                        TRUE : default : {
                        addScore("strengthMax", 3);
                        addScore("knowhowMax", 3);
                        addScore("uuMax", 3);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2235o1") : scoringCon : {
                        addScore("strength", 1);
                        addScore("knowhow", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 1);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2235o2") : scoringInt : {
                        addScore("strength", 1);
                        addScore("knowhow", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 1);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2235o3") : scoringAva : {
                        addScore("strength", 1);
                        addScore("knowhow", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 1);
                        };
                    </stringValue>
                </mvalue>
            </metadata>
            <instruction>
                <text>
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confidentiality&lt;/strong&gt; refers to the measures that your company implements to restrict
                    the access to information should be restricted to only those who need access to it. It is basically about privacy.
                    Said differently, it is about "preserving authorized restrictions on information access and disclosure, including means
                    for protecting personal privacy and proprietary information"
                    (&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://csrc.nist.gov/glossary/term/confidentiality"&gt;NIST, 2022&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrity&lt;/strong&gt; it is the assurance that information is accurate, and reliable. In other
                    words, the protected data or information has not been altered, destroyed or lost in an unauthorized manner. For example,
                    it is about making sure that no web or email address was changed, or making sure that unauthorized people cannot change
                    your data.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability&lt;/strong&gt; guarantees the access to information by/to authorized users and when
                    necessary, i.e. ensure timely and reliable access to and use of data. For instance, it means that things such as
                    keeping your systems up to date, backing up your data or documenting changes are done to ensure your data is available
                    for the continuity of your business.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;For more information you can consult
                    &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.qgcio.qld.gov.au/documents/information-security-classification-framework-qgiscf"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;
                    guideline from the Australian government.&lt;/p&gt;
                </text>
            </instruction>
        </question>
        <question id="q2240" type="A" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-7">
            <introduction>
                Data in transit refers to data that is sent from a device to another over a network, whether that is cellular, W-LAN or
                other networks. It is important to protect these channels from attackers that seek to compromise data in transit.
            </introduction>
            <text>Is data in transit protected against violations of confidentiality, integrity and availability?</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2240o1">
                    <text>Yes</text>
                </option>
                <option id="q2240o2">
                    <text>No</text>
                    <comment>It is important that your company implements the right security measures to protect data in transit.</comment>
                </option>
            </options>
            <metadata key="_cysec.logic">
                <mvalue key="default">
                    <stringValue>
                        TRUE : default : {
                        addScore("strengthMax", 1);
                        addScore("knowhowMax", 1);
                        addScore("uuMax", 1);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2240o1") : scoring : {
                        addScore("strength", 1);
                        addScore("knowhow", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 1);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2240o2") : recProtectDataTransit : {
                        addRecommendation("recProtectDataTransit", 300, "", "", tn("recProtectDataTransit-title"),
                        tn("recProtectDataTransit-text"),
                        "", "app/coach.jsp?fqcn=msesec-data-protection-and-security.default&amp;question=q2240");
                        };
                        TRUE : recProtectDataTransit : {
                        revokeRecommendation("recProtectDataTransit");
                        };
                    </stringValue>
                </mvalue>
            </metadata>
            <instruction>
                <text>
                    &lt;p&gt;When you encrypt data in transit, your company is providing a tangible protection against third party that may
                    try to intercept it for malicious purposes. Consider the following aspects to maintain and/or improve data security:&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Use HTTPS to encrypt the traffic between your browser and websites.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Keep your company's systems and network components updated.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Use encrypted communication when transmitting data over the wireless (e.g. use a Transport Layer Security
                    (TLS) or a Virtual Private Network (VPN)).&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Additional helpful information by the United Kingdom National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC) can be found
                    &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/collection/cloud-security/implementing-the-cloud-security-principles/data-in-transit-protection"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
                    and &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/collection/10-steps/data-security"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
                </text>
            </instruction>
        </question>
        <!-- Priority 4 -->
        <question id="q2245" type="A" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-8">
            <introduction>
                Employees will fail to do the right data sanitization on company's devices when it comes to data decommissioning if there are
                no clear requirements that they should follow. This in return can have devastating results for your business if not addressed.
            </introduction>
            <text>Is data is destroyed according to the requirements?</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2245o1">
                    <text>Yes, we delete data from computers and electronic devices according to the requirements.</text>
                </option>
                <option id="q2245o2">
                    <text>No, we haven't set out any requirements for data deletion.</text>
                    <comment>
                        You need to be aware data might be accessible even after deleting it from your devices. Please make sure that you
                        set company requirements for deleting/destroying data, where it is clearly defined and stated how to do this securely.
                    </comment>
                </option>
                <option id="q2245o3">
                    <text>A third party does this on our behalf.</text>
                    <comment>
                        This is a good solution. However, for security purposes it is important to always make sure that your contractor has
                        the right credentials before handing over your data for them to be deleted.
                    </comment>
                </option>
            </options>
            <metadata key="_cysec.logic">
                <mvalue key="default">
                    <stringValue>
                        not(isSelected("q2245o3")) : default : {
                        addScore("strengthMax", 1);
                        addScore("knowhowMax", 1);
                        addScore("uuMax", 1);
                        };
                        isSelected("q2245o1") : scoring : {
                        addScore("strength", 1);
                        addScore("knowhow", 1);
                        addScore("uu", 1);
                        };
                    </stringValue>
                </mvalue>
            </metadata>
            <instruction>
                <text>
                    &lt;p&gt;Micro and small businesses are also concerned with data deletion. Therefore, you will need to plan for how your
                    company intends to get rid of data in a secure manner. For example, when the contract with a customer, supplier or
                    employee terminates, they may ask you to delete their data. The following aspects should be considered in your
                    company's data destruction requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;When deleting data electronically it is imperative to make sure that it is no longer usable by anyone.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Consider getting a secure deletion software to wipe your company devices (e.g. UBS sticks, computers, flash
                    drives, laptops, tablets or phones) by overwriting data once or several times.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Make sure that the data you wished to erase does not remain in your back-ups.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;For more information consult
                    &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/collection/cloud-security/implementing-the-cloud-security-principles/asset-protection-and-resilience#sanitisation"&gt;these guidelines&lt;/a&gt;
                    by the British National Cyber Security Centre.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Data destruction is the "process of erasing or otherwise destroying data stored on virtual/electronic or physical
                    mediums such as, but not limited to, printed copies, tapes and hard disks in order to completely render data irretrievable
                    and inaccessible and otherwise void"
                    (&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://security-guidance.service.justice.gov.uk/data-destruction/#data-destruction"&gt;Ministry of Justice UK, 2022&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
                </text>
            </instruction>
        </question>
        <!-- Priority 5 -->
        <!--<question id="q2250" type="A" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-13">
            <text>Do you have procedures to temporarily remove sensitive data or systems from the network if they are not regularly accessed?</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2250o1">
                    <text>Yes</text>
                </option>
                <option id="q2250o2">
                    <text>No</text>
                </option>
            </options>
        </question>
        <question id="q2255" type="A" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-4">
            <text>Is there an authorisation process in place that safeguards the flow of information to the outside of the organisation?</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2255o1">
                    <text>Yes</text>
                </option>
                <option id="q2255o2">
                    <text>No</text>
                </option>
            </options>
        </question>
        <question id="q2260" type="A" hidden="false" extRef="DPS-9">
            <text>Do you have sufficient capacity on your ITC assets to ensure data availability?</text>
            <options>
                <option id="q2260o1">
                    <text>Yes</text>
                </option>
                <option id="q2260o2">
                    <text>No</text>
                </option>
            </options>
        </question>-->
        <question id="q2298" type="info" hidden="false">
            <introduction>Data Protection and Security</introduction>
            <text>Coach completed</text>
            <infotext>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Congratulations, you have completed this coach.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Click on «Next» to go back to the overview page.&lt;/p&gt;
            </infotext>
        </question>
    </questions>

    <library id="eu.smesec.cysec.coach.msesec.dpas.MseDpasLib"/>

    <dictionary>
        <entry key="recEncryptMobileDevices-title">Encrypt mobile devices</entry>
        <entry key="recEncryptMobileDevices-text">Encrypt all mobile devices of your company to protect the stored data.</entry>
        <entry key="recApplicableProvisions-title">Get to know regulatory requirements</entry>
        <entry key="recApplicableProvisions-text">Please inform yourself about the applicable law/regulations/requirements that may apply to your business and review them from time to time.</entry>
        <entry key="recProcessDataSecurely-title">Process data securely</entry>
        <entry key="recProcessDataSecurely-text">Your company should process sensitive data securely and according to the appropriate data regulations.</entry>
        <entry key="recSaveDataSecurely-title">Store data securely</entry>
        <entry key="recSaveDataSecurely-text">Your company should meet the applicable data security storing requirements. Make sure to implement technical and organizational measures to protect personal data in your company's possession.</entry>
        <entry key="recRegulationsComplianceImplementation-title">Comply with data protection regulations</entry>
        <entry key="recRegulationsComplianceImplementation-text">Implement the data protection regulations that apply to your business in order to be compliant with them.</entry>
        <entry key="recProtectDataTransit-title">Protect data in transit</entry>
        <entry key="recProtectDataTransit-text">Implement measures to protect your company's data against violations of confidentiality, integrity and availability while it is in transit.</entry>
    </dictionary>

</questionnaire>
